<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Policies on InfoVelocity - Empowering Businesses</title>
    <link>https://infovelocity.io/policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Policies on InfoVelocity - Empowering Businesses</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 09:29:16 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://infovelocity.io/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Reduction Policy</title>
      <link>https://infovelocity.io/policy/carbon-reduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 09:29:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infovelocity.io/policy/carbon-reduction/</guid>
      <description>Infovelocity Ltd Carbon Reduction Policy Effective Date: [08/08/2023] Introduction At Infovelocity ltd, we are committed to mitigating our environmental impact and contributing to a sustainable future.
We recognize the importance of addressing climate change and reducing our carbon footprint. This Carbon Reduction Policy outlines our commitment to implementing measures that aim to reduce our carbon emissions and promote responsible environmental practices.
Our Carbon Reduction Goals 2.1. Carbon Emission Reduction Targets</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Slavery Policy</title>
      <link>https://infovelocity.io/policy/slavery-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 09:29:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infovelocity.io/policy/slavery-policy/</guid>
      <description>Overview Slavery and human trafficking remain a hidden blight in our global society.
Infovelocity has a responsibility to be alert to the risks, however small, in its business and Its wider supply chain. Infovelocity’s employees are aware of the risks and are expected to report their concerns, and management is expected to act on them.
Organisation’s structure Infovelocity Limited, trading as Infovelocity, is a Data Engineering &amp;amp; DevOps consulting firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://infovelocity.io/policy/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 09:29:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infovelocity.io/policy/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>Infovelocity Ltd Effective Date: [08/08/2023] Introduction Welcome to Info velocity Ltd (&amp;ldquo;Infovelocity&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;our&amp;rdquo;). We are committed to protecting the privacy and security of your personal information.
This Privacy Policy outlines how we collect, use, disclose, and protect your personal data when you visit our website or use our services. By accessing our website or using our services, you consent to the practices described in this Privacy Policy.
Information We Collect Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
